# Salahuddin

Jl. Nangka, Gowa, Sulawesi Selatan, 082346462435 salah.huddiin@gmail.com – linkedin.com/in/salahuddin-hafid qithub.com/Dinel13 – dinel.netlify.app

Passionate in software engineering with two years experience developing and maintaining software applications with the latest technology. Strong problem-solving abilities, do the best practices and be eager to learn or adapt to new things then collaborate to build something that can inspire.

## **Professional Experience**

- Software Engineer, tiket.com Payment & Promo Team (May 2022 Now)
  - Developed and maintained software on the backend using **Go** and **Java** with **Spring Boot** to enable a smooth payment and promo system.
  - Utilized database solutions with MongoDB and MySQL, caching with Redis, stream with Kafka and cloud technology with GCP to build robust software.
  - Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver high-quality products on time.
  - $\circ$  Troubleshoot and resolve issues in a timely manner, ensuring minimal disruption to service.
  - Actively participated in code reviews, promoting adherence to coding standards based on SOLID Principle and Clean Code.

## **Project Experience**

- Full-stack Engineer, Jagokan.com (July 2021 April 2022)
  - o Designed and built the entire project, successfully delivering the early version software.
  - Implemented clean architecture on the backend using Go and PostgreSQL. Utilized React.Js, Next.js and Redux for the frontend development.
  - Deployed both frontend and backend on ECS Alibaba cloud with Nginx, ensuring website accessibility for all users.
  - o Integrated with third-party payment provider **Xendit** for secure and smooth payment transactions.
  - Utilized Google APIs for Oauth, Gmail, and Calendar, seamlessly integrating key functionalities.
- Full-stack Engineer, rukisiokal.com (November 2022 January 2023)
  - Designed and built this entire freelance project, successfully delivering and satisfying client requirements.
  - Utilized React.Js, Next.js, Tailwind, Redux and MySQL to build efficient software.
- Undergraduate thesis Microservice System (December 2021 April 2022)
  - Successfully do research and analyze the performance of microservice that use gRPC and REST APIs.
  - Utilized Go and Node.js and deployed on EC2 AWS. Using Apache JMeter, K6 and Datadog to do performance tests.
  - Repo https://github.com/Dinel13/thesis-ac

#### **Education**

- Hasanuddin University Informatics engineering Augustus 2018 - July 2022.
  GPA 3.74/4
- **Bangkit** (February 2021 June 2021) *cloud computing path* program designed by Google with GoTo and Traveloka to prepare students with in-demand skills and tech certifications.

#### **Skills**

- Provide REST or gRPC backend service using Go, Java and Node.js that Interact with SQL database (PostgreSQL, MySQL) or NoSQL database (MongoDB, Redis) and communicate with Kafka.
- Build a beautiful web interface using **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, **TypeScript**, **React.js**, **Next.js**, **Redux**, **Bootstrap**, and **Tailwind**.
- Have experience using several cloud services on GCP, AWS and Alibaba Cloud.
- Utilize tools to help better programming like **Git** with **Github**, **Linux**, **GIMP**, **Datagrip**, **Figma** and **Postman**.